I need y'all to get court watch trained get trained up court watch training this Thursday
and tomorrow we have a special training so you can learn all about why we court watch why we do
this work 135 135 the number of people who were seen in DC arraignment court today that's your
initial appearance the first time you see a judge and in fact arraignment court is still happening
at approximately 10 26 p.m they are locking people up for any and everything four people
were arrested yesterday for being in a public party they arrested a barred attorney we just saw
him in arraignment court like 10 minutes ago and this is what the judge said today verbatim I am
forbidden from ruling on the fourth amendment violations and this is very clearly a fourth
amendment violation because I found probable cause I have to hold you now Trump is trying to hold DC
for ransom all of this shit is manufactured when we've had bail reform on the books as law since
the 90s Janine Pirro her office they don't know what the fuck they're doing do you know how many times
the judge had to come back and be like what is this stay away order what is the government asking for
what is happening this paperwork is not right it's new executive order and Trump's trying to hold
people for ransom people are like oh no cash bail this and that cash bail never went away baby
but what it can be used for is under very limited circumstances and according to section 1321 you
can only put a cash bond for a risk of flight not for dangerousness in DC code section 1329 people
cannot sit in jail just because they cannot afford their bail that's the case the defense attorney can
file a motion and the judge has to lower the bail I've watched Judge Raymond today all day long
reiterate over and over again how she does not have the power to release people even though their
fourth amendment rights have been violated even though there is no real grounds for them to be held
but because they've asked for what's called a b1a hold those holds are non-discretionary that means
the judge doesn't get to choose effectively shifts the power from judges to the prosecutor's office
because all the prosecutors have to do now is consistently ask for a b1a hold and all they
want people to do is plea out at these preliminary hearings and if you don't choose to take the plea
they rescind the plea just like people are fighting in the streets I need people to fight in the courts
I need y'all to get court watch trained I need y'all to be on court support because the violence that
happened with policing that's only the start that same type of violence continues when it gets to the
courtroom this is a shit show if nothing else is a shit show these courts were a shit show before
but they really a shit show now get trained up court watch training this Thursday and tomorrow
we have a special training so you can learn all about what courts all about the courts why we court watch
why we do this work